{"data":[{"question":"Where is Tom?\\nHe _____ (lie) under the car.","a":"is lying","b":"is lieing","c":"are lying","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present continuous to say that someone is in the middle of doing something at the time of speaking ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"2","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"2"},{"question":"It's Tom. He _____ (paint) the front bedroom.","a":"are painting","b":"is painting","c":"is painting","answer":"2","explain":"- He + is + V-ing.\n- paint -> painting.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"2","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"2"},{"question":"Mother _____ (rest) now. She always rests after lunch.","a":"is rest","b":"is resting","c":"are resting","answer":"2","explain":"- She + is + V-ing.\n- Rest -> resting.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"2","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"2"},{"question":"Well, I _____ (go) to the cinema. Would you like to come with me?","a":"is going","b":"am going","c":"are going","answer":"2","explain":"- I + am + V-ing.\n- Go -> going.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"2","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"2"},{"question":"Someone _____ (knock) at the door. Shall I answer it?","a":"are knocking","b":"is knocking","c":"am knocking","answer":"2","explain":"- Someone + is + V-ing.\n- Knock -> knocking.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"2","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"2"},{"question":"Can I borrow your pen or you _____ (use) it at the moment?","a":"is using","b":"are using","c":"am using","answer":"2","explain":"- You + are + V-ing.\n- Use -> using.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"2","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"2"},{"question":"What _____Tom _____(do) now?","a":"is\/doing","b":"are\/doing","c":"do\/doing","answer":"1","explain":"-The question form: Is + he + V-ing...?\n- Do -> doing.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"2","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"2"},{"question":"A woman _____ (wave) from the attic and a fireman _______ (go) up a ladder to help her!","a":"is waving \/ are going","b":"is waving \/ is going","c":"are waving \/ are going","answer":"2","explain":"- He\/she\/it + is + V-ing.\n- Wave -> waving.\n- Go -> going.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"2","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"2"},{"question":"He _____ (clean) his shoes.","a":"is cleaning","b":"is cleaniing","c":"are cleaning","answer":"1","explain":"- He\/she\/it + is + V-ing.\n- Clean -> cleaning.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"2","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"2"},{"question":"Mrs Jones _____ (sweep) the steps outside her house.","a":"is sweeping","b":"are sweeping","c":"am sweeping","answer":"1","explain":"- He\/she\/it + is + V-ing.\n- Sweep -> sweeping.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"2","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"2"}]}